Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Print Matter, 1811-circa 2010; 22.19 Linear feet
  - Subseries VI.C. Miscellaneous Print Material, 1811-1997; 7.25 Linear feet
    - Six Fern Botanicals (Victor Schrager and Martha Stewart Living) [Oversize], 1993 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 8)
      06. Evergreen Wood Fern & Woodland Fragine Fern
    - Williamson, Philemona (artist): Two watercolors--notated "Rikers Island" on back--for the July/August 1985 issue of HSNY's Garden. [Oversize] (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 9)
    - Gourley, Josette (artist): "Vanda Hilo Princess 'Alice'" (limited edition print) [Oversize], 1980s (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 10)
    - Medicinal Plant Map of the United States (National Wholesale Druggists' Association) [Oversize], 1932 September (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 11)
    - Vanderlip Estate, Bedford, N.Y.: Gate renderings (2) by Luther Greene, landscape designer, and Roger Bartels, architect. [Oversize], 1983-1984 (Drawer Oversize-Large)
- Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003; 11.96 Linear feet
  Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries VII.A. Audio Formats, 1968-1996
  Subseries VII.B. Moving Images, 1964-2003
  The Audiovisual series consists of video and audio recordings of activities related to The Horticultural Society of New York. These include meetings, lectures, flower shows, and other programs organized by HSNY. The annual Flower Shows from 1985 to 1995 are especially well-represented.
  The audio format includes thirty-three microcassettes; sevety-nine cassettes; three 6.5mm reels; six 7in. reels; and two 10in. reels. Content includes recordings of HSNY board meetings, lectures given at HSNY, clips from radio shows featuring HSNY programs, especially the flower shows, and radio spots advertising the flower shows.
  The moving image subseries contains fifty-two VHS tapes, five Betamax tapes, four 16 mm film reels, nine 35mm reels, and three CDs. The content consists of advertisements, announcements and news coverage of HSNY programs, mainly flower shows. Included are segments from the Today Show, 1992; Good Day New York, 1993; the Stephen Holt Show, 1991; NJ Cable; Brazilian TV; and a segment featuring Martha Stewart at the 1992 Flower Show. There are a number of copies of a 2003 CBS Good Morning feature on the Greenways Program called "Garden of Hope." Other tapes feature the Green Streets program; El Sol Brillente community garden; and the Garfield Park Conservatory.
  Access Restrictions
  N-YHS lacks playback equipment, so the material in Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003, is restricted.
  - Subseries VII.A. Audio Formats, 1968-1996; 7.96 Linear feet
    33 meeting microcassettes; 56 meeting cassettes; 8 programs cassettes; 15 flower show cassettes; 3 6.5mm reels; 6 7in. reels; 2 10in. reels. Content includes recordings of HSNY board meetings, lectures given at HSNY, clips from radio shows featuring HSNY programs, especially the flower shows, and radio spots advertising the flower shows.
    - Flower Shows: cassettes, 1970-1997 (Offsite-box 90, Box 66)
    - Flower Shows: tape reels, 1984-1987 (Offsite-box 90, Box 67)
    - Flower Shows: tape reels, 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-9)
    - HSNY Meetings: microcassettes, 1999-2004 (Offsite-box 90, Box 68)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1981-1992 (Offsite-box 91, Box 69)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1993-1995 (Offsite-box 91, Box 70)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1996 (Offsite-box 91, Box 71)
    - HSNY Meetings: tape reel, 1968 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
    - Programs and lectures: cassettes, 1973-1996 (Offsite-box 91, Box 72)
    - Programs and lectures: reel, undated (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
    - Unidentified: tape reels, u.d. (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
  - Subseries VII.B. Moving Images, 1964-2003; 4 Linear feet
    This subseries contains fifty-two VHS tapes, five Betamax tapes, four 16 mm film reels, nine 35mm reels, and three CDs. The content consists of advertisements, announcements and news coverage of HSNY programs, mainly flower shows. Included are segments from the Today Show, 1992; Good Day New York, 1993; the Stephen Holt Show, 1991; NJ Cable; Brazilian TV; and a segment featuring Martha Stewart at the 1992 Flower Show. There are a number of copies of a 2003 CBS Good Morning feature on the Greenways Program called "Garden of Hope." Other tapes feature the Green Streets program; El Sol Brillente community garden; and the Garfield Park Conservatory 2002.
    - Flower Shows: Betamax tapes, 1985 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: VHS tapes, 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: film reels (35 mm), 1987-1991 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: film reels (16 mm), 1964-1982 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Flower Shows: VHS tapes, 1992-1995 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Programs and lectures: VHS tapes, 1982-2003 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Programs and lectures: Compact discs, 1990s (Offsite-box 76)
- Series VIII. Reference Files, 1850-2005; 8 Linear feet
  Series VIII. Reference Files, 1850-2005 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries VIII.A. People, 1910-2009
  Subseries VIII.B. Subjects, 1850-2006
  This series consists of the reference files maintained by the Horticultural Society of NY. The series is divided into two main topics: People and Subjects. Each topic is arranged alphabetically. The files include images, journal articles, newspaper clippings, brochures, programs, and biographies related to people and subjects of interest to the staff of the HSNY.
  People include board members and donors, as well as botanists and plant scientists such as Henry Svenson, and landscape architects such as Agnes Selkirk Clark.
  Subjects include topics such as Central Park, community gardens, garden design, greenhouses, landscape architecture, various plant species, and a wide assortment of other subjects.
  - Subseries VIII.A. People, 1910-2009; 3 Linear feet
    - People: A, 1930-2007 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1)
      Abel, Mrs. Murray
      Allen, Charles
      Allport, Alexander
      Appell, Scott
      Auchincloss Family
    - People: B (1 of 5), 1910-2009 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 2)
      Bailey, Liberty
      Baker, Richard
      Barr, William
      Barron, Leonard
      Barton, Benjamin
    - People: B (2 of 5), 1910-2009 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 3)
      Bartram, John
      Bauman, Dina
      Bechtel, Edwin
    - People: B (3 of 5), 1910-2009 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 4)
      Beineke, Elizabeth
      Belcher, Mrs. Benjamin
      Benenson, Sharen
      Benjamin, Herta
      Berkowitz, Mortimer
      Berns, Frank
      Bertron, Samuel
      Blackburn, Benjamin
      Board, current bios
    - People: B (4 of 5), 1910-2009 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 5)
      Brilmayer, Bernice
      Britton, Elizabeth
      Britton, Nathaniel
      Brown, Addison
      Bogart, Ted
      Bogart, Walter
      Bonham, Frederick
      Booke, Ruth
      Boyd, James
    - People: B (5 of 5), 1910-2009 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 6)
      Bryant, William Cullen
      Buck, Leonard
      Bucknall, Ann
      Burbank, Luther
      Burpee, W. Atlee
      Bush-Brown, Louise
    - People: C (1 of 4), 1920-2008 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
      Cabot, Francis
      Canning, John
      Caplan, Ira
      Carle, George
      Carnegie, Mrs. Andrew
      Cary, Mrs. William
      Chatto, Beth
      Cholaris, Betty
    - People: C (2 of 4), 1920-2008 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 8)
      Christiansen, Emil
      Christman, W. F.
      Clark, Agnes Selkirk
      Clark, Elizabeth
      Clark, George
      Clark, James
      Clark, Mrs. Jay
      Clark, Phil
      Clark, Samuel
      Clark, Walter
      Clarke, Gilmore
      Clarkson, Edward
      Clarkson, Rosetta
      Clavey, F. D.
      Clements, Julia
      Clibran, William
      Cloud, K.M.P.
      Cloudsley, J. Rowland
      Cobbett, William
      Cocchi, Antonio
      Cockayne, L.
    - People: C (3 of 4), 1920-2008 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 9)
      Coe, Michael
      Coe, William
      Coffin, Marian
      Coffin, Peter
    - People: C (4 of 4), 1920-2008 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 10)
      Coggan, S. W.
      Colden, Jane
      Cole, Nelson
      Cole, W.B.
      Colflesh, J. William
      Collinson, Peter
      Colman, Jeremiah
      Comley, George
      Conklin, Everett
      Corning, Mrs. Erastus
      Cottle, Donald
      Cran, Marian
      Cronquist, Arthur
      Cromwell, James
      Cross, Mrs. W. Redmond
    - People: D (1 of 2), 1920-1999 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 11)
      D'Agostino, Nicholas
      Daverheim, Mel
      Deitz, Paula
      De La Mare, A.T.
      Dean, Ruth
      Delano, William
      Desmond, Thomas
      Dickson, Alex
      Deitz, Fordyce
      Dorman, Caroline
      Doscher, Alice
      Douglas, Lucille
    - People: D (2 of 2), 1920-1999 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 12)
      Dowden, Anne
      Downer, Henry
      Downing, Andrew J.
      Duke, Doris
      Duncan, William
      Dupont, Henry
      Dupont, Pierre
    - People: E, 1935-2003 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 13)
      Eaton, Jerome
      Edison, Thomas
      Ekstrom, Nicolas
      Elbert, George
      Elwes, Mary
      Emerson, Ralph Waldo
      Epstein, Harold
      Esson, James
    - People: F, 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 14)
      Farnham, Richard
      Farrand, Beatrix
      Farrer, Reginald
      Favretti, RJ
      Ferriday, Eliza
      Field, Marshall
      Fox, Helen
      Free, Montague
      Freund, Karl
      Friedericksen, Ernest
      Fry, Gladys
    - People: G (1 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 1)
      Gaddis, Jane
      Gaden, Eileen
      Gager, C. Stuart
      Galfano, Rose
      Gambee, Eleanor
      Garmey, Jane
      Gibson, Constance
      Gillies, George
      Gish, Lillian
    - People: G (2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 2)
      Greene, Luther
      Goldman, Amy
    - People: G (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 3)
      Gonzales, Ricardo
      Gottscho, Samuel
      Graf, Alfred
      Greenwood, Leslie
      Grimaldi, Marie
      Guest, C.Z.
      Gunnison, Mrs. R.R.
    - People: H (1 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 4)
      Hall, Elizabeth
      Harding, Charles
      Harrington, David
    - People: H (2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 5)
      Haupt, Enid
      Havemeyer, Theodore
      Hay, Clarence
      Hecht, Fae
      Hecht, George
      Hellyer, Arthur
      Henderson, Peter
    - People: H (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 6)
      Herman, Jay
      Hewitt, Mattie Edwards
      Hexamer, F.M.
      Hicks
      Hill, Fanny
      Hill, May
      Hines, Mrs. Walter
      Hines, Linda
      Hodgkins, Ann
      Hosack, David
      Hubbard, Robert
      Hudes, Harry
      Hull, Olive
    - People: I-J, 1963-1999 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 7)
      Iselin, W.E.
      Jack, James
      Jekyll, Gertrude
      Johnston, Vernon
    - People: K, 1925-1999 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 8)
      Kaupman, Dorothy
      Kazimiroff, Theodore
      Kean, Mrs. H.F.
      Kennedy, Margaret
      Kerr, Jessica
      King, Mrs. Francis
      Knapp, Mrs. Arthur
      Kottmiller
    - People: L (1 of 2), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 9)
      Lacerte, Susan
      Laughlin, Cynthia
      Lawrence, William
      Lee, Frederic
      Lee, Patti
      Lees, Carlton
      Legendre, Jacques
      Lemoine, Victor
      Levick, Edwin
      Levison, J.J.
      Levy, Mrs. Louis
      Lewis, Clarence
      Lewisohn, Adolph
      Lindenmeyr, Henry
      Linnaeus, Carolus
    - People: L (2 of 2), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 10)
      Lockwood, Netta
      Lockwood, Mrs. William
    - People: M, 1925-2000 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 11)
      Macy, V. Everett
      Manda, Edward
      Manda, Joseph
      Margolis, Barbara
      Martin, John
      Marx, Roberto
      May, Harry
      Maynard, Walter
      Midler, Bette
      Miner, Frances
      Mitchell, Henry
      Moeller, William
      Moore, Clement
    - People: N-O, 1920-2005 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 12)
      Nash, George
      Newbold, Frederic
      Nordheden, Albert
      North, Marianne
      Otis, Denise
    - People: P (1 of 2), 1919-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 1)
      Pardue, Larry
      Parsons, Samuel
      Payne, Frederick
      Peruggi, Regina
      Peterson, Elizabeth
      Pierson, F.R.
      Place, Mrs. Herman
      Platt, Charles
      Plumier, Charles
    - People: P (2 of 2), 1919-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 2)
      Pollan, Michael
      Powell, George
      Powell, Tom
      Pratt, George
      Pratt, Mrs. Harold
      Pratt, Helen
      Prince, William
      Pyle, Robert
    - People: R, 1930-1999 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 3)
      Rae, Robert
      Ragionieri, Attillo
      Raver, Anne
      Redoute, Pierre
      Reed, Henry
      Rehm, Hans
      Rehman, Elsa
      Robinson, William
      Rodman, William
      Roebling, Mrs. John A.
      Roehrs, Julius
      Rudolph, Emanuel
    - People: S (1 of 4), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 4)
      Sailer, Anthony
      Sanders, Margaret
      Sawin, Mrs. Melvin
      Schlegel, George
      Scholtz, Elizabeth
      Schutz, Paul
      Scott, Robert
      Serlin, Kate
      Scheepers, John
      Schling, Max
      Sheil, Maeve
    - People: S (2 of 4), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 5)
      Sheppard, Arthur
      Shipman, Ellen
      Sloan, Samuel
      Smith, Anthony
      Smith, Georgiana
      Smith, Mary Riley
      Smith, Suzette
      Smith, William
      Smithers, Peter
      Spade, Kate
    - People: S (3 of 4), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 6)
      Spingarn, J.E.
      Steichen, Edward
      Stoltz, Raymond
      Stones, Margaret
    - People: S (4 of 4), 1910-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 7)
      Stout, Arlow
      Strang, Elizabeth
      Stuart, James
      Stufano, Marco
      Svenson, Henry
    - People: T, 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 8)
      Tabor, Grace
      Taloumis, G.
      Thaxter, Celia
      Thorne, Samuel
      Tiffany, Louis
      Tomberlaine, Verdalee
      Torrey, John
      Totty, Charles
      Tozer, Elizabeth
      Trowbridge, Mrs. Cecil
    - People: V, 1935-2001 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 9)
      Verey, Rosemary
      Vester, Bertha
      Voors, H.Y.
    - People: W (1 of 2), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 10)
      Walcott, Mary
      Weber, Nelva
      Webster, Charles
      Weiler, Richard
      Wharton, Edith
      Wheeler, Wilfred
      Wilder, Louise
      White, C.R.
    - People: W (2 of 2), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 11)
      White, Somers
      Whitney, Mrs. Payne
      Wilson, Ernest
      Wood, James
      Woodburn, Elizabeth
      Wright, Richardson
    - People: Y-Z, 1930-2000 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 12)
      York, Lewis
      Young, John
      Zabar, Abbie
      Zinsser, Barbara
  - Subseries VIII.B. Subjects, 1850-2006; 5 Linear feet
    - Subjects: A, 1920-1984 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 1)
      Arbors
      Atriums
    - Subjects: B (1 of 4), 1930-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 2)
      Banks and Slopes
      Battery Park City
      Beans
    - Subjects: B (2 of 4), 1930-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 3)
      Biblical Garden, St. John the Divine
      Biblical plants
    - Subjects: B (3 of 4), 1930-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 4)
      Bonsai
      Botanic art
    - Subjects: B (4 of 4), 1930-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 5)
      Bryant Park
      Brooklyn Botanic Garden
    - Subjects: C (1 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 6)
      Catalogues: seeds and nurseries
    - Subjects: C (2 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 7)
      Central Park
      Central Park Conservancy
    - Subjects: C (3 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 8)
      Central Park Conservancy (continued)
    - Subjects: C (4 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 9)
      Children's gardens
      China: gardens
    - Subjects: C (5 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 10)
      Christmas
      Cocoa
    - Subjects: C (6 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 11)
      Coffee
      Cold frames
    - Subjects: C (7 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 1)
      Colonial gardens
      Community gardens
    - Subjects: C (8 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 2)
      Community gardens (continued)
    - Subjects: C (9 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 3)
    - Subjects: C (10 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 4)
      Companion plants
    - Subjects: C (11 of 11), 1850-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 5)
      Compost
      Container gardens
      Corn
    - Subjects: D (1 of 3), 1900-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 6)
      Delphinium
      Dianthus (carnations)
      Dionea (Venus fly trap)
      Dish gardens
      Dumbarton Oaks
      Dutch Elm Disease
    - Subjects: D (2 of 3), 1900-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 7)
      Dutch Elm Disease (continued)
    - Subjects: D (3 of 3), 1900-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 8)
      Drought gardening
      Dyes from plants
    - Subjects: E (1 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 9)
      Echinacea
      Economic botany
      Edible landscaping
    - Subjects: E (2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 10)
      Elgin Botanic Garden
      Endangered species
    - Subjects: E (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 11)
      England: gardens and parks
      Evergreens
    - Subjects: F (1 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 1)
      Fences
      Floral clock
      Foundation planting
      Fountains
    - Subjects: F (2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 2)
      Fragrance gardens
      France: gardens and parks
      Freesia
    - Subjects: F (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 3)
      Frick Museum garden
      Frost
      Fruit
    - Subjects: G (1 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 4)
      Garden Conservation and Restoration
      Garden Design
    - Subjects: G (2 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 5)
      Garden Design (continued)
    - Subjects: G (3 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 6)
      Garden Furniture
    - Subjects: G (4 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 7)
      Garden History
    - Subjects: G (5 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 8)
      Garden Ornament
    - Subjects: G (6 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 9)
      Garden Structures
      Garden Writing and Writers
    - Subjects: G (7 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 10)
      Gates
      Gentianas
      Germany: gardens
    - Subjects: G (8 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 11)
      Gladiolas
      Greenhouses
    - Subjects: G (9 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 12)
      Greenhouses (continued)
    - Subjects: G (10 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 13)
    - Subjects: G (11-14 of 14), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Subjects: H (1 of 4), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 5)
      Handicrafts
      Hardiness zones
    - Subjects: H (2 of 4), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 6)
      Hedges
      Helleborus
      Herbals
    - Subjects: H (3 of 4), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 7)
      Horticultural therapy
    - Subjects: H (4 of 4), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 8)
      Hydrangea
      Hyacinthus
    - Subjects: I (1 of 2), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 9)
      Ilex (holly)
      Iran: gardens
    - Subjects: I (2 of 2), 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 10)
      Iris
      Italy: gardens
    - Subjects: J-K, 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 11)
      Japanese gardens
      Knot gardens
    - Subjects: L (1-2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 12-13)
      Landscape Architecture
    - Subjects: L (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 14)
    - Subjects: M, 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 1)
      Magnolia
    - Subjects: N, 1930-1990 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 2)
      Narcissus
      New York City: gardens
      North Carolina: gardens
    - Subjects: P (1 of 2), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 3)
      Paeonias (peonies)
      Plant hunters
    - Subjects: P (2 of 2), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 4)
      Perennial gardens
      Perennials
    - Subjects: R (1 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 5)
      Ranunculus
      Rock gardens
    - Subjects: R (2 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 6)
      Rockefeller Center gardens
      Rooftop gardens
    - Subjects: R (3 of 3), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 7)
      Roses
    - Subjects: S (1 of 4), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 8)
      Seaside gardens
      Seed industry
    - Subjects: S (2 of 4), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 9)
      Shade gardening
      Shakespeare gardens
    - Subjects: S (3 of 4), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 10)
      Street Trees
    - Subjects: S (4 of 4), 1920-2000 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 11)
      Sundials
      Syringa
    - Subjects: W, 1930-2006 (Offsite-box 51, Folder 12)
      Women
- Series IX. Memorabilia, 1900s-1998; 4.25 Linear feet
  Series IX contains a small amount of artifactual material from the HSNY, including awards given (ribbons, medals, and an inscribed silver bowl) and received (commemorative plaques), buttons and lapel pins, and some of the hardwood cases that held photographic lantern slides now found in subseries III.C and V.E.
  The smaller items in Series IX--armbands, buttons, ribbons, medals, bowl, printing plates, and diminutive award plaques--are housed in Boxes FF-13 and 83. The larger material--empty slide carousels and wooden cases, and an oblong award plaque--are housed in an oversized bankers box (11 x 15.5 x 25 inches), Box 84.
  - Armbands (7) (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 1)
    INTERNATIONAL FLOWER SHOW | OFFICIAL
  - Buttons & lapel pins (5), n.d. (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 2)
    [1] NYFS | VOLUNTEER
    [2] MEMBER | HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY
    [3] GET GROWING | Join | the Horticultural | Society
    [4] PEOPLE FOR TREES | TREES FOR PEOPLE | H.S.N.Y. [with printed design for same]
    [5] CONTRIBUTOR [lapel pin]
  - Ribbons (7), n.d. (Offsite-box 105, Box FF-13, Folder 3)
    [1] FIRST PLACE [blue]
    [2-3] SECOND | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [red] (2)
    [4-5] JUDGE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [blue] (2)
    [6-7] CLERK | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW | THE | HORTICULTURAL | SOCIETY | OF | NEW YORK [yellow] (2)
  - Awards: plaques (2), 1964, 1983 (Offsite-box 83, Object 1-2)
    Two wooden plaques:
    [1] INTERNATIONAL | FLOWER SHOW | NEW YORK | AWARDED TO | THE HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY OF NEW YORK | FOR | EDUCATIONAL CONTRIBUTION THROUGH THE | AMATEUR AREA | AT THE | INTERNATIONAL FLOWER SHOW | MARCH 1964
    [2] PRESENTED TO THE | HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY | OF NEW YORK | IN APPRECIATION OF THEIR | OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTIONS | TO THE SUCCESS | OF OUR PROGRAM | TIP NEIGHBORHOOD HOUSE, INC. | OCTOBER 14, 1983
  - Award: bowl, n.d. (Offsite-box 83, Object 3)
    Small silver bowl inscribed "THE HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY | OF NEW YORK AWARD | NEW YORK FLOWER SHOW."
  - Medals: Inscribed (11), 1987, 1996 (Offsite-box 83, Object 4)
    [1] THE NATALIE PETERS WEBSTER MEDAL; [reverse] AWARDED TO A MEMBER OR MEMBER CLUB FOR FINDING UNUSUAL PLANT MATERIAL | ENCOURAGING ITS CREATIVE USE AND ASSURING ITS AVAILABILITY | HENRIETTA E. S. LOCKWOOD | 1987 [gold; large format]
    [2] AWARDED TO | SLEEPY HOLLOW RESTORATION INC. | 1987 | NY FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [3] AWARDED TO | TOM THURSTON & CO. | 1987 | NY FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [4] AWARDED TO | MRS. JOHN E. | LOCKWOOD | on April 17, 1996 | flor her devotion | to the library [gold]
    [5] AWARDED TO | 1st PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [gold]
    [6-8] AWARDED TO | 2nd PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [silver] (3 copies)
    [9-11] AWARDED TO | 3rd PLACE | THE | NEW YORK | FLOWER SHOW [bronze] (3 copies)
  - Medals: Blank (16), n.d. (Offsite-box 83, Object 5)